One dream can change the world.
Selma is a history, drama film directed by Ava DuVernay.
"Selma," as in Alabama, the place where segregation in the South was at its worst, leading to a
march that ended in violence, forcing a famous statement by President Lyndon B.
Johnson that ultimately led to the signing of the Voting Rights Act.
Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., played by David Oyelowo.
Coretta Scott King, played by Carmen Ejogo.
President Lyndon B. Johnson, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Lee White, played by Giovanni Ribisi.
Gov. George Wallace, played by Tim Roth.
Andrew Young, played by André Holland.
Selma is a 2014 historical drama film directed by Ava
DuVernay and written by Paul Webb.
It is based on the 1965 Selma to Montgomery voting rights marches which were initiated and directed
by James Bevel and led by Martin Luther King Jr., Hosea Williams, and John Lewis.
The film stars actors David Oyelowo as King, Tom
Wilkinson as President Lyndon B.
Johnson, Tim Roth as George Wallace, Carmen Ejogo as Coretta Scott King,
Common as James Bevel, with Giovanni Ribisi as Lee C.
White, Alessandro Nivola as John Doar, Cuba Gooding Jr.
as Fred Gray and Oprah Winfrey as Annie Lee Cooper.
Selma premiered at the American Film Institute Festival on November 11, 2014, began a limited US release on December 25, 2014,
and expanded into wide theatrical release on January 9, 2015, two months before the 50th anniversary of the march.
The film was re-released on March 20, 2015, in honor of the
50th anniversary of the historical march.
The film was nominated for Best Picture and won Best
Original Song at the 87th Academy Awards.
It also received four Golden Globe Award nominations, including Best Motion Picture –
Drama, Best Director and Best Actor, and won for Best Original Song.
The film explores themes of alabama, civil rights, martin
luther king, based on true story, president.
The tone is emotional.